hello folks uh
welcome to marcellus webinar on our new
fun launch uh it gives me great pleasure
to welcome you all and introduce us to
our new strat
introduce you to our new strategy kings
of capital
it's a financial sector focus fund as
some of you might have
uh realized already um and and this
follows our
successful closure of our small cap fund
the little champs
portfolio again take this opportunity to
thank you all uh particularly the
investors at the fund and also our
distribution partners in helping
close this in what has been fairly
difficult times during the lockdown
so um many thanks for that so without
much ado i'd like to introduce the
portfolio manager of
um of kings of capital tate shah uh a
little bit of introduction about
uh paige before uh before i hand it over
to him uh
paige as you know is is the portfolio
manager he's been a portfolio counselor
with marcellus for the last two years
prior to joining marcellus stage worked
at mayfield el silicon valley
headquartered venture capital fund which
manages three billion dollars globally
at about a couple of hundred million
dollars in india uh
they spent two years as a part of
mayfield's india investment team
covering multiple sectors
including financials and he was being at
the center of india's evolving venture
ecosystem prior to mayfield page was
part of the
equity and capital markets team at ambit
capital where he was involved in the
end-to-end execution of ipos qips and
buybacks
uh this is a chartered accountant and
has cleared all levels of the cfa exam
he holds a b comp degree from ahmedabad
university
uh gives me a great pleasure to
introduce teich over to youth age
thank you pramod um i'll share i'll
share the slides
and and i'll take you and take all of
you through needs
this just one just one sec stage but
pankaj could you please put uh
tager's uh pages the camera on footage
so that uh they can detach his
face
yeah so like all of us know right
over the past six seven years it's been
pretty challenging for the financial
sector as a whole
every year has seen some of the other
challenge pop up for the financial
sector
uh it started with raghuram rajan's
asset quality review in
fy1415 there was demonetization in f516
uh introduction of gst and f517 uh
fi 18 so ilfs and f5 1920 i've already
seen
uh yes bank and bhfl now in what was
already a very deteriorate
deteriorating condition for the
financial sector
um on top of that we saw the kohin 19
knockdown
and that made the situation really even
worse for
by putting further pressure on the
weaker lenders
however paradoxically it is investing in
lenders during these times
that proves to be highly rewarding so
story lines headlines are very similar
in every financial crisis
comparisons are drawn to the crisis of
the 1930s
um solvency of banks is questioned every
time
every time there's a financial crisis
similarly business model of nbfc is this
question
however smart investors end up making a
lot of money
when they invest in the midst of a
crisis like this
so whether it be the crisis of the late
90s or whether it be the 2009 global
financial crisis
if someone would have simply invested in
the bank nifty during the time they
would have made
not only a relative return better than
the nifty itself
but also absolute returns in the
vicinity of 25 30
and that is whether they would have
invested before three months of the
bottom of the crisis
after three months all of those things
in terms of timing don't matter
however that leads us to three questions
that need to be answered
question one is how do we know that the
crisis is bottoming out
is this really the bottom is it not
where are we in the cycle
question two is even if we know that
this is the bottom
how do we know which stocks to select in
within the financial services sector
what should we look out for do we look
at p multiples do we look for value do
we look for growth
do we look at management teams and brand
uh what sort of filters should we learn
and finally after getting one and two
right the third question is
how do we know when to sell uh is it a
buy and hold sort of a strategy like ccp
do we exit at some point of time
um and what will the exit triggers be
like
so we'll take you through through the
slides and try answering each each of
these questions in the coming slides
um i'll hand it over to saurabh to take
you through this slide
fantastic so so uh just one request to
our tech team uh pankaj if you can
just get tager's camera switched on uh
i've got video going from my end but for
some reason i can't see myself
okay is your video on yeah my video is
on as well so just request to pankaj in
the tech team if you can figure out why
and nobody can see us
uh because uh the audience is trying to
see us right so in the meantime
in the meantime i'll carry on
and hopefully hopefully the tech team
can figure out how to
resolve the video issues so folks uh
why are we launching this fund uh in the
middle of a pandemic
uh those of you who attended our 11th or
12th march i didn't forget exactly the
date i think was the 11th to 12th march
that was the day when the market fell 14
you might remember this slide right we
had said on 12th march
uh that uh that the foundations of
india's recovery are
in place and we'd use this uh slide um
and and people had thought that we have
sort of lost our mind right we've lost
our mind
we hadn't right we've thought it through
quite carefully we we believed on 12th
march we believe today
that we are we are beginning a new new
economic
uh we are beginning india's fifth
economic recovery in
in 40 years right so why is that why are
we so confident about that
if you look at india's past in the last
40 years we've had only four economic
booms
right can you see the promote can you
see the slides
yeah yeah i can see the slides see the
slide you can't see us here folks we
know you can't see us we're trying to
figure out why that is
uh uh the tech team is trying to figure
out why you can't see us our cameras are
turned on for some reason
uh uh you can't see us we're trying to
fix that in the meantime we'll
we'll carry on with the slides the
slides are more important than our faces
whilst i would love to believe
that seeing my face will earn you money
it's the slides the intellectual
property
that will help you make money so so in
the meantime let's focus on
understanding the content rather than
rather than worrying about our faces so
so in 40 years we've had four economic
booms in india
the first boom took place 82 to 86 that
was india's first economic boom after
independence believe it or not the
second time our economy boomed was 93 to
96.
third boom was 2003 to 2008 and the
final economic boom the last boom we've
seen in our country was 2009-11 these
are the
only four periods of rising economic
growth in our country and the red
chevrons the red arrows indicate the
same
now before every such period if before
every period of rising growth in india
came a recession in america the first
recession in america
which is relevant for for us is the 79
8081 recession just outside the
uh uh just outside the uh uh the the
timeline of this chart
19 1991 was the same that was the second
recession in america
immediately after that came our second
boom 2000 2001 came the third
third recession and after that was the
was the
third economic boom in india obviously
lehman brothers was a recession
and today america is in recession now
it's important before you invest in a
financials fund for you to understand
why does this happen why does india boom
every time america goes into recession
and to turn it around
why does india never boom without a u.s
recession right why is there a one is to
one correlation
there are two things that are important
for for us to understand
before we invest in a financial fund
firstly
the cost of money the cost of money is
you driven around the world by the u.s
10-year bond e the u.s 10-year bond deal
is the u.s 10-year bond deal is the
world's risk-free rate
as you can see in that blue line it's
been following our entire career
thank god for that but more importantly
folks whenever america goes into
recession
the u.s 10-year bond deal drops by two
to three percent right you can see
every time there's a red arrow see how
quickly the blue line collapses
this time round it's happened as well so
when we began this calendar year the us
10-year bond deal was pushing three
percent
it's zero percent today right 300 bibs
drop in
in six months in the us 10-year bond
deal that means the cost of money
globally has come down
in our country it's come down by 200
bits the cost of money in india is down
by
200 bibs in the last uh three months or
so
our estimation is that we will get
another 100 bits of rate cuts over the
next eight nine months
over the next eight nine months the cost
of money will fall by
another hundred bits or so three hundred
whips drop which is the global cost of
capital drop
we'll see in our country as well right
that's the first critical driver of the
economic recovery
and it's super important for the
financial services sector to see this
sort of drop in the cost of funds
the second driver of our economic boom
in our country tends to be low oil
prices
right that's the orange line in this
chart right so no surprises when america
goes into recession
the price of oil drops right if after
all the if after all the world's largest
consumer of oil
if the world's largest consumer of oil
goes into recession
oil prices drop by 50 to 80 percent you
can see this in this chart right see the
sharp drop in 84 91 2000
uh 2000 2001 2000 2001 the price of oil
gradually slid
from the high of 2000 to 911 basically
fell by 50
and 2008 and 2008 we were down by 70 80
this time also this year as well price
of oil has halved right why is price of
oil having a big deal
because the drop in the cost of oil
gives us a three percent of gdp boost
right it's happened this time as well
the bulk of the government's fiscal
largest was the oil price drop right
there is something more left there
given the drop in the cost of oil so
india booms when we get cheap oil and
cheap money courtesy of u.s recession
we are in that phase right at one level
it's a no-brainer to say
that after the contraction in the
economy in april may you can't possibly
see any other thing but back
back to rising growth so we highlighted
this slide in march
it's important that if you if you are
thinking of investing
in the financials fund or generally in
india you need to understand this
this is critical and this has laid the
foundations as we said on 11th march cap
down day
this is laid the foundation for for uh
for the
beginnings of an economic recovery so
now back to page for you to understand
why
in such a climate of low low and falling
interest rates
of recovering economic growth why it
makes sense to invest in
in in stellar financial services
companies
so and that slide tries nicely with
where are we in our in our growth
recovery in the financial sector itself
um like we've seen many times over in
the past 20 25 years
uh we've seen periods of crisis followed
by periods of recovery
and that is inevitably inevitably
followed by a period of
economic growth um and this keeps on
happening in india over and
over again in the financial ecosystem
however what is important to note is not
all sorts of lenders or all financial
institutions
go into the recovery period or in the
period of economic boom in the same
shape and form
that they entered that they entered the
crisis
so for example uh if we would have gone
gone through the 2009 crisis uh then
a lot of poor quality lenders suffered
on the liability side as well as the
asset side
and not all types of lenders are able to
recover at the same rapid pace
during the period of recovery um and
that is where
that is where uh we've focused on
uh to answer question number two on our
previous line uh
what sort of lenders or what sort of
financial institutions do we pick
um if we were to take the example of
hdfc limited in the crisis of the late
90s or the early 2000s
uh they entered the crisis with 16 17
roas however they exited the crisis with
23 24 percent rues
so like in any other crisis uh npas of
hdfc limited doubled
uh nps went up from half a percent in 96
to one percent in 99 p ratios half
p ratios came down crashing down from
twenty times to eight nine times
and therefore therefore uh the share
price
work had a double impact one was because
nps double second was because p ratio is
hard
however what is interesting to note is
what happens post the crisis
uh what is the crisis the loan book
growth starts accelerating
roes are better off than they ever were
and
because of that p e ratios start
normalizing
um an hdfc bank also same storyline
during the 2009 global financial crisis
np has increased from one and a half
percent to two percent uh
p e ratios came crashing down from about
28 29 times to 18 times
and they exited the crisis with roes
which were much better off
than the entry roas and the reason that
this happens is
uh these high quality lenders they not
only have
enough capital on their balance sheet to
survive the crisis
but they also are in a position to raise
capital
and they have the ability to raise
growth capital to gain market share post
prices so while 80 percent of the ndfc
sector got wiped off
in the crisis of the late 90s uh hdfc
limited was able to raise liabilities at
will
um and was able to raise liabilities at
the interest rate
that it was willing to offer to these
lenders
similarly on the asset side during such
a crisis because competition gets
completely wiped off
uh these lenders are able to pick the
credit quality of their choice
uh and lend to these guys at the
interest rates that they want to offer
this leads to better better asset
quality and this leads to better net
interest margins
eventually as a result of this roe start
improving p
ratios start normalizing and and
investing in these financial quality
in these high quality financial
companies gives you
three three different benefits one is
acceleration in normal growth
second is normalization of npas and
finally
normalization of pa multiples
to take you through how we've created
this portfolio
um what sort of filters are we run and
to answer the question on
what sort of financial companies do we
invest in um
we started out with a universe of about
100 companies
and these were companies in the
financial sector obviously which
included banks nbfcs
insurers brokers and asset managers then
we ran our forensic filters on these are
under companies so in some ways this is
very similar to what we do in ccp and
nct
however i'll take you through the
forensic filters uh which are bit
different because these are financial
companies in the coming two slides
um and we eliminate about a third of the
universe over here here itself
so about 30 35 companies don't create
don't don't pass our forensic filters
and that is because these are companies
where corporate governance is an issue
accounting quality is an issue and we
can't trust their numbers
so about a third of the universe gets
eliminated here itself
then on the remaining 65 stocks we run
our
capital allocation filters here we try
and assess
whether over the past six seven years
these companies have been able to
generate
returns on capital well above cost of
capital
so we look at about 10 11 ratios uh
and we try and assess whether these
companies have been able to do
profitable lending over the past six
seven years
whether net interest margins are
improved or not over a period of time
secondly are they providing enough for
npas are provisioning
coverage ratios good enough to protect
the balance sheet
have they generated return on equity
which is better off than the cost of
capital consistently over the past six
seven years
and over here again half of these 65
stocks more than half of these 65 stocks
get eliminated in this filter itself
um and we finally come to a consolidated
list
a short list of 23 stocks and
it is here that most of our research
effort most of our time is spent on uh
it's on doing deep work on these 23
stocks
so filter number one we try and we try
and uh
filter out companies which have who are
accounting quality for corporate
governance
filter 2 we try and remove companies
which have not generated returns well
above cost of capital
and in our qualitative work on these 23
stocks
what we try to figure out is whether
these companies
have sustainable competitive advantages
as
a result of which they will be able to
generate returns on equity
which are much above the cost of capital
and the way we try and do this is uh we
we do a lot of independent channel
checks so for banks we'll try and meet
collection agents we go and meet dsas
branch officers
credit officers so
[Music]
in the case of insurance companies we'll
go and meet actuaries uh
we'll meet insurance agents brokers
and the same is the case with asset
managers and
brokers we try and collaborate what the
management is trying to tell us
by speaking to people who are doing the
work on the ground uh
in all these different fields so we go
and speak to management teams
we speak to ceos people who are
previously on the board of directors
and that is how of these 23 stocks
we've created a portfolio of about 12
stocks
um and take to take you through uh the
details of our forensic filter
how how have we built this filter so
there are about 11 ratios
and we rate all our all our financial
companies from d1 to d10
so d1 stands for decile 1 d1 being the
best
d10 being the worst so the ratios that
we use are
say for example free income as a
percentage of net interest income
so in the case of yes bank for example
free income as a percentage of net
interest
income was 54 percent versus for other
lenders
it's between 25 to 30 percent so for
example for a co-talk
it's at 28 similarly contingent
liabilities
as a percentage of net worth uh say for
yes bank it's 23 times
versus for a quota kits four times and
it's on these ratios
that we try and rate all these financial
institutions
we compare banks to banks nbfcs to nbfcs
housing finance companies to housing
finance companies and so on and so forth
so it's a comparison between peer sets
and then
we try and rank them between a d1 to a
d10
so from an academic exercise it looks
good right
uh but what we've already tried to do is
uh
we've also tried to find out the
correlation with stock price returns
so if we would have created a portfolio
of financial companies
which rank between a d1 and d3 and
invested in them over the past three
four years
we would have generated a ten percent
key card uh
similarly if you would have created a
portfolio of financial companies which
rate between a d8 to d10
that would have generated a keger return
of minus 25 percent
so a simple mechanical way of creating a
portfolio
just on these forensic filters would
have generated a massive 35
alpha over a period of the past four
five years
so we realized that this is an extremely
powerful filter uh
without companies uh bases accounting
quality
not only in terms of accounting quality
but also in terms of direct correlation
to share price returns
uh to take a a case study
uh an example of a company on where on
which we run our forensic filters
was dhfl so in the case of dhfl
just on the basis of its f530 into fy 18
published
and uh this was when dhfl was growing 20
25 percent
year on your fi 18 was when the hfl was
at its peak
it was well before uh the thing became
completely public and well known
so there were three red flags which were
primarily
which primarily came to our our
knowledge
one was similar to sort of similar to
yes bank
free income as a percentage of net
interest income yes bank
amongst its peers was the second worst
um so it had a fee income as a
percentage of net interest income at 25
which was second only to reliance on
finance
and what this does is this improves
and makes and makes you believe that the
pl is much better than it actually is
so profitability improves our return on
equity improves profit margins net
interest margins improve
while the balance sheet may deteriorate
at any point of time in the future
similarly treasury income has a
percentage of net interest income
again it's pumping up the p and l
the pnl looks much better than it
actually is because of these non-core
non non core accounting items
and again in this case dhfl was the
third worst amongst its peers
another interesting thing that dhfl did
was it routed a lot of
expenses through its balance sheet
rather than the p and l
so for example it issued thousands of
thousands of crores of zero coupon bonds
and ntds
the interest on which was being set off
against securities premiums and general
results
uh and as a result of this again the pnl
looks much better
than it actually is so these
these ratios finally what that resulted
into
was that dhfl was a d10 which is the
worst score on a forensic model
for two three four years before it came
out in the public
um and that is why we continue to use
for
our forensic model as the first filter
to eliminate companies without companies
which are poor quality accounting
now coming to our portfolio construct
the way this portfolio has been
constructed
is that it's a 60 40 sort of a mix 60
to lenders 40 to non lenders
um and what that does is that the
lenders give us
over a period of time of good good alpha
and the non-lenders in the portfolio
reduce the volatility in the portfolio
so what we look at for
within all these sub sectors is one we
look at good accounting quality like we
discussed
two ability to generate roe is well in
excess of cost of capital and three
is in each of these cases they should
have high barriers to entry
so for example in the case of life
insurers or general insurers
we look at long term long term uh
actuarial risk
frameworks which have generated which
have generated
good results over not only the past
three or five years but 10 15 20 years
so good good underwriting across
multiple cycles
similarly in the case of asset managers
and brokers we try and look at business
models which have strong pricing power
and great amount great amounts of
operating leverage
um and as a result of that if we were to
look at
say fi 20 as an as an example
uh while uh lenders faced a challenging
time in the past two
three months we saw that brokers retail
brokers have been growing 70 80
year on year similarly general insurers
because 50 to 60 percent of the business
comes from motor insurance
uh saw that they were seeing a lot less
claims than
they were seeing in the previous years
because the country was
under the lockdown for about three four
months uh
and obviously because of that uh
vehicles were not flying the road
general insurance saw a straight flow
through to their bottom line because of
lower claims and motor insurance
similarly is the case with life
insurance uh
every time you see a pandemic or a
health crisis
health insurance awareness and life
insurance awareness improves drastically
so we see that see that recovery for
these non-lenders
not only in terms of business
performance but also
quicker recovery in terms of stock
prices
and as a result the portfolio's
construct is such that there is not a
high amount of correlation
between these sub-sectors despite being
a portfolio which is focused
on the financial ecosystem so we've
tried to capitalize
not only on the lending industry but
also on the structural
savings savings growth story in india um
and to and to make that point uh make
that point even better
uh and emphasize on this uh if someone
would have invested in the portfolio two
years ago
if they would have invested on first of
april 2018 uh
this financials focused fund would have
made twelve percent returns
versus five percent for a nifty or minus
two percent for bank nifty
and this is with volatility
which is lower than the index
which are much better off than the nifty
and the bank nifty
so this is despite the last two years
having seen almost everything you've
seen rlfs collapse u.s bank dhfl
and now the covet crisis and the reason
for this is
the table on the bottom left our core
focus on fundamentals
and high barriers to entry results in a
portfolio
which over the past five years in
difficult times
having generated 19 earnings growth and
rvs and the numbers for the indices are
extremely dismissed so not even worth
comparing
earnings worth one percent for the nifty
um
and as a result of this as a result of
this this portfolio would have generated
uh even in f5 20 returns which were much
better off
which were much better off than the bank
nifty and the nifty and even in absolute
terms
which were much better off than the rest
of the rest of the stock market
um and despite being a finances focused
fund uh we get a lot of questions around
volatility
here a lot of questions around
correlation with with the indices
so despite being a financial focused
fund uh
the standard deviation is lower than the
index and
sharp ratios are much better off than
the nifty similarly
because of the non-lenders being 40
percent of the portfolio
the correlation of the non-lenders is
just 26
with the nifty versus versus 95 percent
correlation of the bank nifty with the
nifty uh so we believe
that over a period of time um as as the
fund
as as the fund progresses over the next
two three four years
the volatility will will be similar to
what we have seen in the last two three
years much lower than the bank nifty
and similarly the returns will obviously
be much better off because
or because of our core focus on the
fundamentals of the portfolio
now to answer question number three
which we saw earlier
when do we exit or when do we sell uh
how would we know that
so we've got two three approaches on how
we think of
think about this approach one is
that we invest in such a portfolio
during a crisis like this
and we hold on to it for three four
years uh
and previous prices have shown us that
holding on to such a portfolio for three
four years
gives us good absolute returns good
relative returns in the vicinity of
about 25 percent
um and if we sell out three four years
out
if someone would have invested in 2008
nine sold out in 2013-14
uh they were
from the drag that happens three four
years out so
three four years out of a crisis uh the
bank nifty gives maybe say minus two
percent or five percent
and we can save ourselves from the drag
on the portfolio from from by exiting
three four years out the second approach
is
that that as fund managers are as
portfolio managers
we look at the number of ipos or the
number of qips that are happening during
the year
so every time in the past decade we have
seen
a large number of ipos in the stock
market that has been followed by a large
drawdown
uh whether it be 2007 whether it be 2010
or 2017
uh the biggest drawdowns have always
been preceded by a large number of ipos
and qips in the market
and that is linked to a third approach
when there is easy money available to
all types of lenders all types of
financial institutions
that is a sign of a raising economic
boom in india
so if we look at the cpc cpcd yield and
treasury yield
and the spread between these two numbers
and we see that the spread is narrowing
that is a sign that poor quality lenders
are able to raise money at rates
of which high quality lenders are also
able to raise that
um and once we see that that is a sign
of a raging economic move
so once we identify or look at these two
three factors we have a couple of
options in front of us
one is three four years out when we see
a rating economic boom in india
we start tilting our portfolio toward
towards more higher quality lenders say
towards the hdfc banks or the cortex of
the world
the second option is that we tilt our
portfolio towards the non-lenders within
the portfolio
that is towards the insurers asset
managers brokers
um and what that does is like we saw in
the previous slides
it improves or reduces our volatility on
the portfolio
and gives more stability to the
portfolio in case of a drawdown
um and that is how that is how we've
thought about
what we do three four years out once the
economy
covers once we've made 20 25 percent
sort of returns on this portfolio
and to finally take you through our
thought process on the sort of stocks
that we have selected in the portfolio
and why we have selected them
um let me take you through three case
studies
one is on bajaj finance second is kotak
and third is hdfc bank
so in all all three of these companies
each of these companies
three themes are common uh the three
themes being
uh great corporate governance good
accounting quality
second being ability to generate returns
on capital available cost of capital and
historical demonstration of the same
and thirdly uh high barriers to entry
uh the difference in each of them is
they have created different each of them
has different strengths
and they have created different barriers
to entry in their own own different ways
so for example in the case finance why
we like bajaj finance
over the past 10 years they've made
they've made
they've made huge amounts of investments
in technology and big data
and that is the barrier to entry for a
basaj finance
uh unprecedented amount of investment in
data analytics
and today they finance about 75 percent
of india's consumer durables
so the amount of data that finance has
on about four and a half crore consumers
in india
and to add to that 17 financing 70 to 75
percent of india's consumer durables
every year they can not only they can
not only at a very granular level
know what these customers are doing but
can easily cross sell about 15 to 20
more products
which they already have in them so for
example
using this funnel of consumer durables
financing they cross sell home loans
they cross sell mortgages lab lab that
is run against property
gold loans lifestyle financing digital
financing etc
and 70 of their existing disbursements
are made to customers whom they've
already financed in the past
uh and to take one more example the
granularity to which they go
so there are about 10 lakh doctors in
india
now bajaj finance has mapped out
each and every doctor in india and they
know which doctor
passed out of which college and when did
he pass out
then they've graded each of these
colleges so if a doctor has passed out
of the top 100 colleges
they gave him a score x if he is passed
out of the bottom 100 colleges they will
then another filter that they apply is
whether he lives in a city like mumbai
whether he lives in a rural
town uh and then when has he finally
passed out
uh this is this they've categorized each
of these 10 lakh doctors into 600
different clusters
and this is on only one product they've
done this for each and every product
and as an as and when time goes by as
they keep gaining market share
as they keep financing these guys their
data only keeps on improving
and this when you combine it combine it
with the liability
side of bajaj finance its ability to
raise capital
at the rates which are amongst the best
in the nbc industry
that is a very powerful combination on
the liability side you are
able to raise capital at the lowest
rates on the asset side
give the technology of a small fintech
player and the agility of a startup
uh and that is why we keep on holding
the bazaar's finance and keep adding
to our position even in ccp in bajaj
finance
the second example is uh
bank uh what kotak has done over the
past 25 years is
is this brilliant capital allocation in
some ways even better than hdfc bank
so over the past 25 years they started
out with a small retail
in bfc business uh and then a securities
business
uh what they did was they started
learning from the global best
in each of their in each of the
industries that they wanted to enter
into
so they entered into jv with four credit
they entered
in into a jv with goldman they learned
life insurance from old mutual
and so on and so
and once they got the banking license in
2003 they gave an exit to each of these
players
and now all subsidiaries of quota bank
are 100 percent owned
um and once they got the banking license
so they had two challenging
challenges in front of them one was
being a retail focused lender
how do they build out a corporate loan
book and second was
how do they build out a large liability
franchise which is focused on granular
retail deposits how do they build a
granular casa franchise
so again this problem was attacked
brilliantly by way of capital allocation
uh during the crisis of 2009 when
everyone was receiving from
from the lending corporate lending
market kotak doubled its corporate
room book in 2009 uh they took the call
of doubling down on corporate on the
corporate room book
and they grew again in 2009 10 by 50
so that is how they achieve the good
balanced diversified loan book mix
similarly in 2012 13 they started
offering higher interest rates on
savings accounts at six percent
um and then at that point of time there
are questions around whether you can
sustainably build a casa franchise by
offering higher rates
but over the past seven eight nine years
they have now
become the best in terms of having a
casa franchise
at 56 percent they have the highest casa
ratio
amongst the major indian banks so over
the past 25 years
they've not only built out multiple
financial services businesses by
learning
from best in the world but they've also
built out from being a retail lender
retail focus lender to being a
diversified lender and building a great
casa
franchise now finally coming to hdfc
bank
now a lot of us know about their systems
and processes
and that is what has resulted into the
past
25 years of unsurmountable growth
uh gain in market share and impactable
asset quality
and they've they've continued to focus
on mitigating risk
and focusing on processes and that
eventually leads to the outcomes and the
numbers that we see
um and to take an example right uh how
how do they focus on these systems and
processes
one of one of the group heads at hdfc
bank that we spoke to
he reported to aditya for 15 20 years
and he told us that
an axis versus an icici versus an hdfc
maybe an sdfc bank
would would become just comparable to
these people on on a
person-to-person basis or in terms of
bank strength or in terms of talent
however where sdlc bank won the race
over the past 20-25 years was
on systems and processes by simply
following these processes
they've they've not only kept
continuously grown at 20-25
but they've grown grown at this rate by
keeping
np is at about one one and a half
percent uh
and that is why we believe whether the
ceo remains the same whether there is a
change in ceo whether there is
whether there is an internal candidate
or an external candidate
hdfc bank is at an extremely is on an
extremely strong footing
at least for the next two three four
years
um and finally coming to the fund
structure so
we'll offer two options to our investors
option one is a two and a half percent
fixed fees uh
and option two is one and a half percent
space
with a fifteen percent profit over a ten
percent total
uh and the minimum remains the sebi
minimum which is 50 lakhs
yes that is it from my side
great so so we've got a whole host of
questions coming in uh page and sort of
so i guess uh
a lot to get ready for a bit of a ride
um
yeah i mean they keep coming in i'll try
and bunch them up into
a few categories so that we can try and
take as many questions as we can
the first question is
the people have sort of burnt their
fingers in thematic
funds historically there was a way when
there were infra funds and there was a
way when
the pharma funds of course summer funds
have outperformed in this rally but
for the long run you know the experience
of having invested in sector specific
funds haven't been particularly great
naturally because it offers poor
diversification
and at the same time a financial
specific fund
adds its own source of volatility um
how how would we justify uh someone
investing in a in
in the kings of capital fund and
particularly given say in
in the nifty most indices including our
own ccp has a fairly high weightage
towards uh
financials as well and how how do we
justify the need for a
financials only so i'll have a first
crack at that
uh you can then take over from me so
folks
we heard this line of argument when we
launched little champs
back in august 29th august 30th august
when we launched this line of argument
a lot of people told us that you know
small caps is a
is a graveyard you know everybody else
gets buried you'll also
you'll also get buried and in fact kings
of capital is not even small cap right
kings of capital is ha
sub bse 500 so we heard this dire uh you
know pronouncements about how
various people had lost money and
obviously you know we are very sensitive
to that because
our job is to protect money uh more than
anything else
um and and as we and as we've built this
portfolio the little champs portfolio
uh invested it and remember before we
launch a portfolio
we use our own money to make sure that
that we know what we are doing here
you know we've become even more doubly
sure of the of the mantra that we
that we've applied to consistent
compounders which is that there's only
actually one mode of investing in india
at one level
it's not as if there's any difference
between large cap small cap financials
non-financials
that one mode of investing in india the
only mode of investing in india that
works is
you have to look for companies that are
clean right where your forensics your
research on the promoter suggests he's
not a
is not a chore that's the first pillar
second pillar is look for companies that
are selling products services
which are essential to life in what is
still a very poor country
whilst two thousand dollars might be our
overall per capita income that's
flattered by
people like you and me the vast majority
of the country next one some on
income much lower than that um so so
look for companies that are selling
essential products and services
and the third thing is look for
companies with barriers to entry higher
than mount everest
right all three of these especially the
forensic bit and the barrier to entry
bit
takes a lot of work and if you do the
work or your fund manager does the work
uh you'll make money if you or your fund
manager don't do the work
it does not matter what you invest in
you can do large cap micro cap mini cap
infrastructure financials you will get
destroyed in this country
right the whole ecosystem in the stock
market the bond market
is meant to help you lighten your wallet
right there's nobody out there who's
gonna try to help you make money
right so the first focus whatever we do
whatever you do with your money
has to be look out for fraudsters if you
don't mind just go to that slide where
the forensic picture you were showing
right
or the super tighter thought there's a
suit there's a remarkable bit in that
forensic slide
so so we'll just look at pages forensic
slide
and assume for a minute that neither he
nor nor v in marcellus have any
intelligence that we are
duffers and look at the bottom line
bottom left
panel what that is telling you is if all
that we do
is focus on the top 30 percent of
financial services companies right
assume we have no intelligence about
you know barriers to entry and when to
enter when to exit all of that assume
goes to hell
we just focus on the forensics piece
you can see you'll make money in
financials right and by the same token
uh for those of you remember the
corresponding slide for the broader bsc
the same piece holds true the top two
tiers on accounting quality in the bsc
500 disproportionately make more money
than the rest of the bsc 500. so so at
one level this whole
debate around the sector fund is
actually somewhat distracts from the
point that what we are building here
is a high class portfolio built around
clean accounts
essential services and very high
barriers to entry
the second thing the second reason for
doing it remember is
is how india has evolved right two three
four years ago whoever tried a financial
services fund had no choice he just had
to do lenders
there was nothing else listed in our
country uh till
three four years ago in terms of
non-lending financial services you
didn't really have too many life
insurance listed
uh you didn't really have too many
general insurance listed you didn't have
any asset managers listed
you didn't have almost any wealth
managers are listed
so so the len the financial services
ecosystem is sell mushroomed
from just being lenders to a more
all-round all-around sector
and this will continue right the savings
story basically the story you and i are
part of as we sit on a friday evening
discussing investing the savings story
uh is going to run for a long time
95 of india's wealth is in real estate
and gold that's rbi study super study
the 2017 rbi household finance study
95 of india as well as in real estate in
gold that's not tenable
india will shift from 95 to 80 20 80
percent of our wealth will be physical
and five percent 20 will be financial as
opposed to 95.5 today
india's wealth india's stock of wealth
is around 10 trillion
that means today 9.5 trillion is in
physical assets barely half a trillion
is in financial assets
as we go to a more 80 20 picture india's
financial
assets over the next 10 years will go
from being half a trillion to
potentially two to three trillion
we cannot you i cannot uh not
participate in that
process of investing in good quality
insurers asset managers wealth managers
right
so that's the second piece to consider
leaving aside the focus on forensics and
rigor and forensics the second piece to
consider is the sector shaping up in
front of you
you yourself are contributing to the
growth of the sector and millions of
people like you and me
will will drive the growth of of the
lending sector and
sorry the insurance sector and the asset
management sector
the third piece to consider is is why is
look at the background in which we are
doing this
historically 70 of our lending ecosystem
has been public sector banks right all
of you know that 70
of our loans are psu banks psu banks as
all of you know make no money right the
state bank of india hasn't made an roe
above cost of capital
for i think 20 years right so these
banks perpetually live on
taxpayers funded dole out you and i get
taxed we give money to the government of
india
government of india slams it into the
psu bank balance sheet and the psu banks
then take away 70 of the loan book
of the market um the government has no
money to put in psu banks anymore
right financial fiscally you know what
the state of the country is right uh uh
given the fisk it is impossible to now
conceive
how the government will support the 70
of the lending ecosystem which is
psu banks even if you assume 70 car 10
years my 50
right their india situation right where
psu banks exist but for the half dead
and even if they go from 70 to 50 in the
next 10 years 20
market share opens up who will that
market share go to that 20 percent that
will open up
will it go to middle of the road nbfcs
who struggle to hold it together
or will it go to bajaj finance will it
go to middle of the road private sector
banks whose books are as cooked as page
was indicating the names
on these forensic slides or will it go
to hdfc bank and kotec bank
we don't think it requires a great leap
of imagination to figure out that
as we go through a consolidation in the
in the in the lending universe not just
psu's but even in the private sector
lending universe
the top lenders will win big you heard
from us over the last two years
how in every sector in india whether it
is pain whether it is
a footwear whether it is a glass lined
vessels
whether it is biscuits cooking oil one
or two players
in every sector in india are ending up
taking home 80 85 percent of the
sector's profits
the same thing will happen in lending
over the next decade or so
we cannot not play that dynamic the
consolidation and lending
as the government support for the psus
gets taken away
and as the weakest week of private
sector guys get weaned out
people who are in the zone of thuggery
and zone of opacity those private sector
lenders get decommissioned
so structural opportunity on the savings
side as you and i
save more through financial products and
less through
a a real estate and gold
and we want to play that through
insurers asset managers and wealth
managers
and structural opportunity on the
lending side this is the time to do it
you gotta start after a crisis
because you're getting the benefit of a
full economic cycle in front of you
so to our mind you're getting you're
getting a high quality portfolio
in a sector which i think several of you
already told us is one third of the
market
you're getting a portfolio diversified
across the best lenders
the best asset managers the best general
insurers the best life insurers
the best wealth managers why you
wouldn't want to invest threat i
honestly can't figure it out
so page over to you any other thoughts
on this subject please feel free
yeah just to add to that this is a
sector also right
for congregation because if you look at
any other sector right which
which which are the weakest players in
any other sector they are the ones which
are highly leveraged
uh so in this sector given that it is a
sector which is inherently leveraged
the the pace at which consolidation will
happen
will be much much more quicker than what
what happens in other sectors
uh because weaker ndfc is because weaker
banks
don't have the ability to raise keep on
raising liabilities
uh it's far off for them to keep on
going balance sheets
they will struggle to raise liabilities
to survive through the crisis
it is a sector which will consolidate
much more quickly
during a crisis like this than many
other sectors
great um so the next question is about
the inherent volatility in financials i
think i think you did touch upon it
somewhere during this
slide but given the number of questions
that have come on that
um how do we intend to manage this
volatility how do we intend to manage
this risk
if you can give a sense of what sort of
drawdowns do you expect for example if
say let's see
if we get a second wave of covet and
extended lockdowns and stuff
or perhaps some other crisis given the
inherent nature of the leveraged
nature of financials how do we intend to
manage
and if if say uh toggling is part of it
what sort of churn ratios can one expect
in in this sort of uh in this sort of a
fund so
so days if you don't mind i'll i'll have
a first crack at that
so just i just stay on the slide so
firstly folks as
as they just indicated the fund is
toggling between 60
lenders and 40 lenders so general
insurers
life insurers asset managers and wealth
managers so obviously if you do have
let's take
the promo promote scenario which is
second wave of kovit
another bout of irrational hysteria like
like we were gripped in march where
people thought the whole country is
going to somehow go fall off a cliff
uh the the non lenders obviously will
fall less right the non lenders will
fall less
and that buffers your portfolio but at
one level
you don't want too much buffering
because then you and i can't get those
opportunities like we got in
april may to load up on on great lenders
so let's
let's take the ccp as a case study of
how this portfolio will work right
so for those of you are unaware uh
between january february march
the market fell around 30 consistent
compounders fell
12.9 in spite of
bajaj finance falling i think 70 percent
hdfc bank stays falling 50 percent
yeah yeah and kotak bank following
summing as much right so
the three lenders in our portfolio the
three lenders in our portfolio
collectively
would form around uh of the three
lenders added up would be around 28
of ccp fell uh uh the best part of 50
and yet yet ccp fell 12.9
right not only did that buffer us on the
downside
through april may we got a great
opportunity to load up on
on three world-class lenders uh as the
market panic
so we want a little bit of volatility
this is stock market this is not a fixed
deposit
we want a little bit of volatility what
we don't want you to do is suffer the 30
drawdowns which other fund managers have
made you feel is
part and parcel of life in our country
and the structuring of the portfolio
will give you insulation from massive
drawdowns at the same time it will open
up opportunities for us to
buy great lenders every time india goes
through a panic like covet
page over to you yeah so uh
if someone say would have invested even
in f520 right if someone would have
invested in this portfolio on first
april uh 2019 um
so 100 rupees invested on first april
at the end of the financial year that is
on 31st march 20
which i believe was i think the lowest
point uh lowest point
in the stock market 100 rupees would
have become 90 rupees so that's a 10
product versus the nifty voice minus 25
percent
so minus 10 percent versus nifty is
minus 25
and the bank nifty was minus 37 percent
so this buffering is a result of one
being of course the nonlenders in the
portfolio and secondly
high quality lenders in the portfolio
sorry the next question is around
something that goes against marcellus is
uh you know
a basic grain of not trying to time the
market
this seems like it's all about timing
what has changed
and how do you justify this change so
you know we can't time the market we
don't try to
what we can do and that's why we exist
and we
we manage your money is we can spot
uh investment opportunities in
industries which are
consolidating we've done exactly the
same in little champs folks in little
champs we've gone in
uh in little champs we've gone and
bought sector champions
whether it be in glass line vessels uh
gmm foddler whether it be aliphatic
amines alkylamines
and and that ability to realize that
a said company a certain company is
clean
is firstly part of our forensics team's
job the forensic team gives the clean
shade
that this fellow is not stealing money
the second job is to figure out is there
a robustness in the demand for the
product
in financial services that is quite easy
i mean i don't think anybody on this
call will dispute that
we need life insurance we need general
insurance we need
asset management and we certainly need
lenders
so the essentiality bid is is quite easy
actually here but the hardest part of
the job remains
the barrier to entry piece right so i'll
share with you one
factoid one sort of experience of
assessing barrier to entry on a
on a stock which we have put in ccp and
which will also feature
inside portfolio hdfc life it took us
one and a half years of research to
figure out
why hdfc life has built a barrier to
entry that no other
insurer has built right the the barrier
to entry in htfc live around big data
around data analytics around actuarial
science
and how that leads to superior
underwriting
superior return and embedded value which
in turn leads to better better
generation of capital reinvestment of
that capital back into the life
insurance business
that process took one and a half years
and i think we must have met
uh in that journey we must have met
around 20 distributors of life insurance
products obviously met all the life
insurers
we met several actuaries we met around
30 x and current staff members of the
life insurance industry
that's where the hard work goes and
that's bloody hard to figure it out
right
the instinctive thing the lazy analyst
will say
was sbi life yellow sbi live they got a
great branch network
or they'll say i approve life little i
threw life is
it takes bloody hard work to figure out
of the three
which is the one with the sustainable
competitive advantage
right that's what makes uh a quality
investing stand out
we don't try to time the market what we
spot is sectors where
you can see one or two players are
becoming dominant and they will drive
consolidation
we have spotted the same in the
financial services industry
as i said a few minutes back the lending
consolidation will be partly driven by
the government not being able to finance
psu banks and it does not matter which
political party by the way there is no
money left to finance psu banks right
so the lending consolidation will be
driven by
the government not being able to finance
psu banks and to be fair to the ruling
dispensation
they've already said there'll be
basically five psu banks everybody else
can
go and jump into the arabian fee and
then the private sector lenders
consolidation will be driven by
uh integers forensic chart the the zone
of thuggery basically being
decommissioned as the mutual funds stop
stop buying their commercial paper in
asset management
and wealth management you folks are
going to try the story
and again where it's pretty apparent who
the dominant
dominant players will be both an asset
uh and in wealth management
um and our job is to spot these
opportunities and make money from it
that's why we exist we enjoy doing it it
gives us a kick to spend your
year and a half researching a sector
identifying the dominant
uh dominant uh dominant player the one
with the strongest barriers to entry
and then we put that to work once people
like you give us give us money
great this is a very interesting
question a few people have asked it
um they said that one of the things i
liked about merciless
was deep understanding of a handful of
companies to get
to the bottom of the issue this is
marcellus's third fund in
literally less than two years
doesn't that go against the grain of the
merciless philosophy of having a
concentrated list of companies so that
you can get to the
depths of of each of these companies
no super question folks so just to give
you some perspective on
us um we've been working together as a
group
promote rakshith and i for 16 years
paige
page has worked with me for the best
part of seven years now
um ashwin shetty the little champs a
little champs fund manager
he's worked with me for 12 years now
right so
so we have 12 analysts in the team and a
12 analyst fund manager in the team
and we've spent you know over a decade
together with each other
in those in that decade that we've spent
you can i hope you won't forgive us for
figuring out around 40
odd companies in our country across
large cap small cabinet cab right
so ccp plus little champs is around 25
companies um uh
several of you asked whether the stocks
here are fresh or there'll be
regurgitation of ccp and little champs
this portfolio is likely to be as they
just said around
10 to 14 stock portfolio right assume
say 13 14 stocks
of those 10 to 14 stocks seven will be
seven will be drawn from ccp and lcp and
another seven odd will be
uh will be common uh seven of five
actually sorry
five will be drawn from tcp lcp and
another seven eight will be
will be will be unique to this portfolio
so
so we've got 12 analysts between 12
analysts we currently look after around
26 stocks roughly two stocks panelists
this at the creation of this portfolio
will add another seven eight
stocks to our stable off to our stable
our coverage universe table so to speak
and we'll end up with around 35 stocks
that we have to
tend and look after across a uh a 12-man
man uh there is one lady in the team so
11 men and one lady
12 percent team uh so that's around
three stocks per
per analyst um and that gives us
abundant time to spend
a good year researching away researching
away
a stunt company before we put your money
to work there
at one level i wish there was more i
could discover for you but our
journey in india across the last 12
years suggests that the
the list of companies that are
investable across say the top 1500
stocks in our country
the list of companies that are
investigable is probably limited to 50.
once we once we get kcp going on monday
i think the first monies will flow in on
monday
um once we get kcp going on front monday
our coverage universe will be 35 out of
those 50 stocks
and hopefully in due course the other 15
will will bring under
coverage but 12 analysts three stocks
panelists
abundant time to do in-depth research
and honestly that's the piece
that we enjoy the most we do we
we do speak uh in these webinars because
it's a occupational thing if you don't
speak to you how will you know what
we're doing
but the real kick is uh is doing
forensics
uh spending time reading annual reports
and and doing primary data research
that's what all of us get a buzz out of
and we get great abundant opportunity to
do that in this job which is why we are
sitting in front of you today
okay the next one is the opposite of uh
the markets looking risky um the
opposite is
well timing is nice but isn't it a bit
too late uh
the last three months has seen
significant rally in the market
and even financials have rallied
somewhat
and given that the capital raising
environment at these
level of stock i mean stock prices is
healthy won't the weak lenders be
also be able to bolster their balance
sheet and hence their
consolidation team get jeopardized so
the reason page is a fund manager is he
preempted this question page take
take us through that slide where you
should know what happens if you invest
too late and too early and so on right
timing is irrelevant
yeah so see if someone would have
invested not at the bottom of any of the
previous crisis
even if they were three months late
three months early
they would have made a healthy 23
percent in 2009 a healthy 32
in the crisis of the late 90s and
speaking of the financial stocks right
now
uh even if we were to compare them to
the pre-pre-crisis era
uh they are still lagging behind the
market rally so
while the market is 10 15 20 percent of
its peak
uh if you were to compare it to the pre
crisis era
these financial stocks are still 35 40
percent bank 50 is still 35 40 percent
of its peak even if we were to speak
about those numbers
so let's look at it another way that 23
number page gave you right he's saying
that even if you screw up the timing and
assume we will screw up the timing right
we
as i said we have no great insight into
market timing even if you do that you
get a healthy return but there's another
way to think about it right the simplest
way
please take us to the earnings growth
slide percent is
slide so we are investing in market
leading franchises whether it's in
life life insurance or or lending life
insurance already giving you the lame
lending
it doesn't take a genius to figure out
some of the lenders in the portfolio
right these are companies who are
growing earnings the bottom left table
earnings at nineteen twenty percent
if a company's earnings grow nineteen
twenty percent year after year
right how much return will they generate
from your shareholder return perspective
hopefully easy answer 19 20 right so
believe it or not uh this portfolio
generates the same earnings growth as
nestle
with with similar volatility as nestle
right
so so so it sounds very
counter-intuitive that baby mill powder
grows at 20
and so does hdfc life but that's
actually the answer and that's why we
get
we gravitate towards stocks like hdfc
live hdfc bank
bank bajaj finance we gravitate towards
stocks like this
uh high quality companies who who have
shown
over 10 years as integers was
demonstrated returns
of 20 20 earnings growth because if
that's there
you and i will make twenty percent that
you know provided you don't you and i
don't try to time the market
your earnings growth and your share
price return are broadly uh commensurate
to each other
and that's what you end up with if you
leave market timing aside
right uh so this will be a 10 to 14
stock portfolio
somewhere between those two and sixty
percent lenders 40 percent non-lenders
20 earnings compounding volatility
similar to that of the nifty
but return substantially better than the
nifty
yeah i think this has to be my favorite
question uh
i think a couple of people have asked
but i think it's a very important thing
not many people realize which is the
risk from change in management
almost all the four case studies you
refer to have either
already seen a change in management or
is impending
uh either in the short or the median
term
how do you how do you address that risk
as part of your investment process
so super question uh maybe said the
question person is going to ask the
question should perhaps become part of
our investment committee
we need minds like this so folks you can
guess what subject
we've spent and i personally have worked
on this over the last 12 months
uh last 12 months we've created a
probably i think probably the most
powerful framework created in our
country
for assessing uh succession risk right
so
this i think the question is are you
doing two what will happen to hdfc bank
post
what could happen to kotak bank and and
what might be the post to their quota
given the way the rbi is going right uh
uh nanu pavnani uh one of the big brains
behind bajaj finance passed away
uh recently what impact will nanuji's
demise
have on on this great lender right
hdfc live amitabh left and joined access
bank
and and and they they had an internal
succession
there right what impact did it have on
hdfc lie so what we have done over the
last year
is created a framework to look at this
very clinically right there's no
emotions involved you know we're not
related to any of these promoter
families or these
ceos or cfos we are here to make money
and we built a framework around
around three things firstly this is our
research talking to staff members in
these places
is there a ongoing succession planning
program not just for the big man or
woman at the top
but for the cfo the cto for the
retail deposits head for the retail
liability franchise head
if you don't spot a an ongoing
succession program
for every layer of the of the corporate
hierarchy
we give lower marks to that company
second thing
how strong is the board in the sense are
the
other fellows sitting on the road
drinking buddies
of the ceo slash promoter or are there
people
that we know from our from our social
life a strong minded people who won't
mind letting it rip at the board meeting
you know people who have got an
independent mind and character of their
own right so we scoring we scored the
boards of
of these companies right and this is
across all our portfolios folks
so quality of ongoing succession
planning at every level of the hierarchy
not just the big man
quality of the board and thirdly uh
basis uh our analysis of incentive
structures
uh esop structures uh how how
decentralized is the compensation
framework or is it the case at the year
end
malik sits down and decides
right the more granularity we've picked
up in our chats with
uh dsa's feet on street
brokers distributors of these various
companies the more granularity more
decentralization
the more autonomy we've picked up the
greater marks we have given
because a more decentralized construct
is more robust
and more uh able to deal with our
changes in management right so we've
scored the entire
all the portfolios for that and the same
is being done to
kings of capital and companies which
have more robust
succession planning uh constructs not
just at the big at the top level i
stress
right so remember at a lender even more
important than the ceo is potentially
the
head of risk if your head of risk gets
run over by a bus
and you suddenly say was discovered
ahead of risk and let's hire from some
other place
you are screwed as a lender because in
that period when your head of risk has
been run over by a bus
and you have no other candidate uh your
loan book could blow up right
uh so so we've scored the companies that
we're investing in
basis the rigor in terms of uh quality
of board
quality of succession planning and
decentralization of corporate might and
corporate decision making
so the more granular it is the more
higher the scores you get
now obviously none of this is sort of
perfect in the sense
in spite of all of this we could get hit
by a black swan but as they say
as they say in golf the harder you
practice the more you prepare
the luckier you get and you seem to be
very lucky over the
last couple of years and how our
portfolios have performed
great so i think we need to get into uh
some of the uh sort of housekeeping
questions but before that one question
on asset allocation
we have several of our clients and
thanks for that they have invested in
both the ccp and lcp and they're keen to
invest in kcp and they ask this question
while investing in lcp as well
how should they divide their corpus
between a ccp and lcp now that you've
thrown this into the mix what should be
the ideal split if i have hundred rupees
and i want to give all hundred rupees to
marcellus
how should i split it between ccp lcp
and kings of capital
so when we were uh uh when we when we
had lcp open
and and and you know we i suppose i'm
we are really sorry that we have to
close it to influence but we can't help
it there is no
stock left in the market to buy in those
in those counters
but when we had lcp open when people
asked us this we said if you
invested 100 rupees in ccp invest 33
rupees in
in lcp right because lcd is illiquid
in liquid both in the sense that we
can't find that much stock in some of
these super
sub dsc 500 names and in liquid in the
sense that were you to try to suddenly
tell us one day
even for us it's hard to liquidate those
positions post haste
so we said 100 rupees in ccp logic
suggests 33 rupees in
lcd here our suggestion will be for 100
rupees in
ccp you do 50 rupees in kct the
liquidity here is far greater uh
because you know hdfc live hdfc bang
these are large
large companies plenty of liquidity in
the market uh remember rvi has said no
promoter can't hold more than
20 so so the liquidity is all out there
in the market so this is these are large
liquid companies
and secondly the inherent
diversification in the portfolio between
lenders and non-lenders
you can quite literally see in front of
you on that in that table page is
created
how that buffers your volatility you're
getting returns comparable
returns better than the significantly
better than the nifty or bank nifty with
volatility which is comparable
so i would suggest if you have 100
rupees in ccp you strongly consider
putting
50 rupees in kings of capital
okay um a related question to that
is uh i guess you've addressed the point
of risk
how should one think in terms of
expected returns if one is considering
a three to five years investment horizon
from this fund
page over to you yeah one should expect
uh 20 to 25 out of this um
over a three to five year period on top
of on top of
this theme of earnings gigger improving
over the over the next three to five
years on the basis of consolidation on
the
back of credit growth coming back um one
would also expect
these high quality names to start
growing more and more rapidly over the
next five years
as the sector gravitates and
consolidates towards them
and um is this a closed-ended fund like
lcp
do you have a capacity in mind how are
you thinking about how much
this sort of strategy can absorb and
also um
will you ever think of returning capital
if if at the
peak of the next bull market you reckon
there are no opportunities
how should one think about that
page you want to take that first yeah
sure so
uh in terms of capacity of the fund
definitely it's much more liquid than an
lcp than lcp
um so we don't expect that over the next
few months or over the next year
its capacity could be filled up but of
course there is a theoretical capacity
which anyways here ccp would also have
but we don't expect that capacity to be
reached over at least
next one year uh just one caveat to that
folks i think
we are assuming uh a degree of sanity
into the flows in kcp
if uh if the flows into case if we rock
it through then
then uh then uh you know we obviously
could be left with the challenge that
uh the four five five say the five
smallest names in the
the five smallest names in the kcp
portfolio if we realize that liquidity
is draining up because the fund
inflows are coming very quickly we might
have to put up uh some sort of gate
again
in terms of stopping inflows but as
stage is saying the working expectation
should be that
it will remain open for for the next
year couple of years
uh i you know we can't commit because of
the sheer
ill liquidity at the lower end of the
portfolio
um the other thing is there is no exit
load here
right so as because the reason there is
no exit load is
is uh uh uh there is enough liquidity if
you were to tell us that you want your
money back
you should be able to honor that by
selling your stock in the market
in uh in lcp obviously little chance
there's obviously
uh there's obviously an exit load
because it is that much harder to
to uh uh to to exit those stocks uh very
quickly
right so does that mean it's going to be
a
relatively large cap biased how do you
think of sort of market
cap buyers for the fund page average
market cap median market cap
median market cap 55 000 crores uh but
it will be
the range is pretty wide um anywhere
between half a billion dollars all the
way up to hdfc bank
about 100 billion dollars median market
cap being 55 000
so just to contextualize what they just
said
consistent compounders median market cap
is 1 lakh
60 000 crores yeah consistent
compounders
median market cap is one lakh sixty
thousand crores
uh a little champs medium market cap is
uh is the best part of of
say three thousand crores yeah little
champs medium target cap is three
thousand crores
uh so therefore this number that page is
giving you
of ten thousand ten thousand close
reducer
fifty five thousand fifty five thousand
crores right so fifty thousand thousand
crores
is basically halfway between
halfway or uh yeah so some somewhat
halfway between
the the punchy market cap of consistent
compound is 1 lakh 60
and the incredibly low market cap of
little champs and that gives you a sense
of why we had to
shut little champs because those really
are precious gems
uh uh 3000 crores companies with
dominant positions in
in sectors which are essential to life
so this is more liquid mercifully
than little chance and hence we can
should be able to keep it open for a
couple of years at least
and uh how do you look at deployment
typical marcellus style pretty much
deploy immediately taking liquidity into
account or given there's an element of
timing here will you will you sort of
wait it out stage yeah we'll deploy
immediately
just like we do in all other funds
taking liquidity into account
great um just one last housekeeping
question a lot of you have asked that
if you can split uh your 50 lakhs
across all three funds uh i'm afraid we
can't
um i mean this is a 50 lakh limit for
each of marcellus strategies and it's
not a regulatory constraint it is it is
a merciless
requirement that you need to invest at
least 50 lakhs in
in each one of them there are a few
questions uh
we're avoiding about uh what do you
think of
specific sub-sectors like depositories
and rating agencies
and stock exchanges um i think given the
given the uh uh you know literally each
of these subsectors have one stock
um i don't think we would like to
comment at this stage
uh over time as we publish our
newsletters
uh there will be more commentary on the
on the portfolio composition
um so until then uh folks uh thank you
thank you very much for
uh dialing in uh feel free to write to
us if you have any further questions uh
feel free to write to your wealth
management partner
happy to answer as many questions as we
as we have until then have a good
weekend and stay safe
thank you thank you
you